Humira Alam Frontend Developer



humira87@gmail.com

+880 1334501411

in /Humiralam/

😯 GitHub:HumiraAlam

About me

As a passionate Frontend Developer, I specialize in creating dynamic and interactive web applications. My core expertise lies in React, along with strong skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, Redux, Redux Toolkit. I also have experience with REST APIs & responsive design. I am familiar with several project & team management tools, CI/CD tool such as GitHub Actions for smooth deployment. I am well-versed in Agile-Scrum methodologies & work well in a team environment. I possess excellent analytical and problem-solving skills, & always ensure my work adds value to the customers.

Areas of specialization

- Clean, efficient, maintainable coding
- Responsive web interface
- Consider best UXpractices
- · Version control

Further Interests

- Backend Technologies
- · Linux & DevOps

Leadership

- Trained junior resources in JS
- Acted as a Scrum Master in several sprints
- Conducted Web Development Bootcamp

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sep 2023-Current

Trainee Full-stack Developer (MERN Stack)

SITA.DEV · Sweden (Remote) 9

- Developed front-end projects with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React.js, ensuring responsive and dynamic interfaces.
- Followed Agile and Scrum practices, participating in sprints, stand-ups, and retrospectives for timely delivery.
- Cross-team collaboration using Git and GitHub, managing repositories and performing code reviews for a clean codebase.

Feb 2019-Nov 2020

Web Analyst- SEO, Digital Content

LEARNIO · Denmark 💡

- · Managed, optimized website content for better UX and search engine efficiency.
- · Analyze web data to drive site functionality improvements and user engagement.

Jan 2017– Jan 2019

Digital Strategy, SEO

REVE Systems · Bangladesh ♀

 Website optimization, branding action planning for digital platforms, monitoring implementation, tracking progress, and fixing analytics errors to meet KPIs.

Jan 2015-Jan 2017

SEO Consultant | Content Manager

Up Arrow Consulting · Bangladesh 9

 Worked for Websites' SEO, Content strategy development, web traffic generating, and progress report tracking.

DEGREES

2022 MSc in Digital Leadership

University of Gothenburg · Sweden in

2013 **BSc in EEE**

United International University

· Bangladesh 🏛

Programming

HTML5, CSS3 Sass Bootstrap

Media Queries JavaScript (ES6+)

React Redux Toolkit

TypeScript REST APIs WordPress

Tools -Technologies

CI/CD Tools Project-Management Collaboration

Team-Management

GitHub Actions Jira, Trello, Basecamp, Miro, Microsoft 365, Google Workspace

Discord, Slack, Confluence,

Clockify

Remote-Working Zoom, Meet, Teams

DIGITAL SKILLS

Agile-Scrum UI/UX basic

SEO Rank Traffic-Web Analytics

Content Writing-Editing

Technical Presentation Mentoring

LANGUAGES

Bengali English Swedish C2 CEFR-C1 SFI-C Mother tongue

• • • •